# **Aleksandr Nikiforov**

alexander\_kif@mail.ru • https://www.linkedin.com/in/aleksandr-nikiforov-8a417712a/

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Frontend Developer with 4+ years of commercial experience crafting web applications. In my projects I've used ReactJS and VueJS (Vuetify, Quasar framework). For the last 2 years I've been working with Angular 13 and Jasmine for unit testing. Open to relocation anywhere in Canada except the North Pole:)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## front-end Web developer

EPAM Systems • Antalya, Turkey

Jun 2021 - Present

Last two years I have been writing an app for a big staff-management company using Angular. This work is in a large team and involves collaborating with the other large teams. We used on the project hundreds of branches in BitBucket, many jobs in Jenkins, images in Docker, and the NodeJS layer.

Before it I was working on a project using VueJS and Vuetify. I added some new functionality to the existing SPA for the oil company including new report tables, analytics and statistical graphs, charts and diagrams, modifying the existing data-model. My team consisted of 1 Front-End (me), 1 Back-End, 1 BA, 1 QA.

## front-end Web developer

Oct 2019 - May 2021

S.K.A.T. • Krasnodar, Russian Federation

I independently created three SPAs using VueJS and the Quasar framework for a municipal public service center. The first is intended for recording and managing tickets for queues to see specialists. The second is intended for collecting statistics and creating reports on citizens' requests with graphs and diagrams. Finally, I replicated an existing Delphi program into a modern SPA for internal use on a local network for service center management and scheduling. Additionally, I collaborated in a large team to build a React-based web application for a medical institute so that doctors could train and test their students.

# **Network Infrastructure Support Engineer**

Feb 2018 - Sep 2019

CJSC Greenatom • Glazov, Russian Federation

Cisco, Layer 2.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Informatics and Computer Engineering**

Sep 2017 - Feb 2022

Izhevsk State Technical University (ISTU) • Izhevsk, Russian Federation

You can see some educational projects on my GitHub.

https://github.com/alexanderkif

## **Multichannel communication systems**

Sep 1997 - May 2000

Moscow Technical University of Communications and Informatics (MTUCI) • Moscow, Russian Federation

## SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, SPA, PWA, React.js, Angular, Vue.js, Quasar Framework, Vuetify, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Jasmine + Karma unit testing.

## **AWARDS AND HONOURS**

First prize in the Robotics category of Junior competition in MOSCOW ENGINEERING PHYSICS INSTITUTE 2017

I was the project manager for my son. Our project won the Junior competition in NATIONAL RESEARCH NUCLEAR UNIVERSITY MEPHI (MOSCOW ENGINEERING PHYSICS INSTITUTE) in the category Robotics. We made a Solar tracker on an Arduino microprocessor, SCADA system for saving the results of the experiment to a computer using the RS-485 protocol. Look on my LinkedIn or directly <a href="https://alexanderkif.github.io/solarTracker">https://alexanderkif.github.io/solarTracker</a>